Bhumika Gaurav Bisht

bhumikabisht786@gmail.com

\+918630339653

Portfolio link: https://bhumika0201.github.io/cv2/

LinkedIn link: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bhumika-gaurav-bisht-9a3871179/

Summary

Self taught programmer with close to 5 years of work experience in front-end and back-end engineering.

Diversified professional career varying from MNC to Freelancing to being core tech member of Best startup in software category by Silicon India 2013 and most innovative product at Net app accelerator. I have maintained developed and launched multiple projects from scratch carrying development of its Back-end and Front-end code bases.

Apart from coding

Manage events as part of AFWWA (Indian Air Force Wife's Welfare Association), AIR 49 in International Math Olympiad Certification in Aero-modeling, Certified in Decoupage art.

Coffee lover who is up for new challenges.

Experience

Senior Developer

BlobCity Dec 2020 – Present (9 months+)

Project Lead for IOS and Android Mobile Application for Long Dog Ventures Ltd

Application Name: My Box Ticker

Mobile Application that lets you compete with your friends on same bucket list items

- Worked on UI and logic part on frontend.
- Worked on major parts on camera integration, image library, profile sections, push notifications for both android and IOS.
- Made API's on node for the comments, followers and following, likes, image uploads, posts, excel uploads and converting it to hierarchy.
- Deployment to IOS through Xcode and Google Play Store
- Project Lead for Underwriters Laboratories(Web & Mobile)

This platform allows UL Inspectors to upload checklists of standards (Ex NFPA) and conduct assessment of compliance for worldwide listed hotels based on same

- Built an entire application that allows the UL Inspectors team to carry out their surveys based on compliance of various standards on web and mobile platform effectively.
- Being one of the only 2 developers in the back-end team, planned the entire architecture and developed the entire product from scratch.
- Developed 5 modules single-handedly and owned their complete responsibility from end to end.

Mobile application that allows UL Inspectors to conduct assessments remotely

- Collection of data while connected to internet saving the data in mobile's memory
- Conduct of assessment offline and synchronization of data when the phone is connected to internet
- Released beta version in test-flight for IOS
- Mobile Application for WRG(World Bank Group)

Simple mobile application that calculates consumption of water in a year based on household appliances used (desert coolers, refrigerators, washing machine etc). Based on difference in consumption of water per year and average consumption unit /country generates WRG certificates to promote and educate on saving water.

- Worked on UI and logic part on frontend
- Worked on API for calculations of WRG certificates
- Deployed the application in IOS Test Flight .It is currently in beta testing
- Al Cloud Platform (BlobCity)

BlobCity's AI cloud platform enables user to launch a GPU-enabled Notebook from your browser in seconds. Notebooks are fully-managed and do not require any setup or management of servers or dependencies.

- Made the important modules(Projects ,Datasets ,Profile, Resume) completely for the project including the front end in angular and backend APIs in node
- Made the custom nbviewer to see the code
- Made the major fix in the project on opening Cloudbooks .Earlier the Cloudbooks could be created only by entering the password for the jupyter notebook which made the customer experience not so comfortable Now the Cloudbooks don't require password and can be opened with ease .This was a major change in the way Cloudbooks were used .
- Made the snapshots section for the cloudbook where the snapshots can be made with every change in cloudbooks
- Stripe gateway for payment integration

Full Stack Developer

BlobCity Sep 2019 – Nov 2020 (3 Months)

Contract with BlobCity (Upwork) Dec 2019 – Aug 2019 (9 Months)

Team Lead for IUCN(International Union for Conservation of Natural resources), Mongolia

Built an effective SaaS platform for collection of Climatological data worldwide and analyzing impact on Groundwater resources for International Union for Conservation of Natural resources. This is currently being used by the Mangolian government

- Based on data, the charts were plotted and compared between different timelines, weather parameters collected (Pressure, Temperature, Hardness, Wind speed, TDS, etc) and different sources of collection.
- Multilingual application using internationalization that could switch language between English and Mongolian
- The prediction for groundwater was shown based on Time series forecasting
- Competitive Analysis Tool for Jaguar Land Rover

This tool allows comparing MRP's of all the car models worldwide and choosing between features in company's own car model to evaluate correct budget for the car .My role in this was to integrate charts for plotting data

Visual charts (BlobCity Internal Project)

This platform allows user to generate charts of different types by providing data in correct format The frontend is made in angular that can be integrated to any project with the iframe

- The data is sent to APIs in a format having parameters for chart type output required etc
- Backend is made in node for making APIs that give the desired data for output in JSON format
- Chart for the project is plotted based on output received in a particular format based on chart type

MEAN Stack Developer

Freelancing Apr 2019 – Nov 2019 (8 months)

Developed E-Commerce website for Today Book House.

Software Developer

Tata Consultancy Services Jan 2017 – Mar 2019 (2 years 2 months)

- BaNCS (TCS Banking Solution) which provides Backend banking support to its clients .Whenever a
 transaction is made in front end by cashier or teller, through different gateways it reaches backend
 wherein after all validations transactions are made and updated in database. Made backend changes in
 programs based on customer requirements using Cobol and Unix
- IBM Integration Bus for making web services
- Built complete POC individually in angular that could translate in English and Japanese using internationalization .It took user data and sent it to Xml, filled existing pdf form through the user entered data and saving data in Mongo database

Educational Background

Honors Awardee in Mechanical Engineering

G.B Pant Engineering College Pauri, Uttrakhand

Skills

- Client handling
- Team Lead
- Project Lead
- MEAN + MERN stack developer
- App Development and management

Languages and Tools

- React Native •Node JS• Python (Django framework) XCode
- Angular SQL Git Angular C#(.NET) Git• Java C
- Jira Cobol NET Core •Unix Jira C++